# 1607年 #
# In sixteen hundred seven #
# 我们航行在广阔的大海上 #
# We sailed the open sea #
# 为了荣耀 为了主 为了金子 #
# For glory, God and gold #
# 还有维吉尼亚公司 #
# and the Virginia Company #
# 也为了天堂一般的新世界 #
# For the New World is like heaven #
# 我们将会富有和自由 #
# And we'll all be rich and free #
# 就像维吉尼亚公司 #
# Or so we have been told #
# 告诉我们的那样 #
# by the Virginia Company #
# 就像维吉尼亚公司 #
# So we have been told #
# 告诉我们的那样 #
# by the Virginia Company #
# 为了荣耀 为了主 为了金子 #
# For glory, God and gold #
# 还有维吉尼亚公司 #
# and the Virginia Company #
- 准备好吊起加农炮了吗? - 好了
- Ready to hoist the cannon? - Right!
嗨 看 那是Smith吗?
Hey, look. Is that Smith?
就是他 没错 那个老练的水手
That's him, all right. The old sea dog.
John Smith船长?
Captain John Smith?
我听说过很多关于他的惊险故事
I've heard some amazing stories about him.
你也参加这次航行吗?
Are you coming on this voyage too?
显然 你个笨蛋!
Of course he is, you half-wit!
没有John Smith 你别想和印第安人打交道!
You can't fight Indians without John Smith.
没错
That's right.
我可不想让你们这些小孩 去独享航行的乐趣
I'm not about to let you boys have all the fun.
# 在Virginny的海岸 #
# On the beaches of Virginny #
# 有石块大的钻石 #
# There's diamonds like debris #
# 有银子做的河流在流淌 #
# There silver rivers flow #
# 金子在树上采撷 #
# and gold you pick right off a tree #
# 一块送给我亲爱的 #
# With a nugget for my Winnie #
# 另一块留给自己 #
# And another one for me #
# 然后剩下的全部归于 #
# And all the rest will #
# 维吉尼亚公司 #
# go to the Virginia Company #
# 这是荣耀 这是主 这是金子 #
# To glory, God and gold #
# 也是维吉尼亚公司 #
# And the Virginia Company #
抛下所有的锚!
Haul on the brace!
加油 伙计们! 加油!
Come on, come on!
谁 来帮帮我!
Do your best!
当心!
Watch out!
快点! 更多水涌进来了!
Faster! She's taking on more water!
当心!
Look out!
John! 快点过来!
John! Get down here!
绑加农炮的绳断了!
The cannons are breaking loose!
- 把帆收起来! - 是的 先生!
- Reef the topsails! - Yes, sir!
稳住
Steady on your course.
没事 Thomas! 我们来将它绑好
It's all right, Thomas. We'll get her tied off.
祈祷吧 伙计们!
Say your prayers, men!
Thomas 当心!
Thomas, watch it!
救命!
Help!
有人落水了!
Man overboard!
救命!
Help!
待在你们自己的地方! 他已经没救了!
Stay your course! He's lost!
救命!
Help!
- 打开钩子! - 是的 先生!
- Pull the pins! - Aye, sir!
Smith啊!
Smith!
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
坚持住 Thomas 我够到你了!
Hang on, Thomas! I've got you!
快! 绳子!
Quick! The rope!
拉!
Heave!
加油 伙计们! 使劲拽!
Come on, lads! Pull!
拉! 拉!
Pull! Pull!
尽全力拉啊!
Put your back into it!
- 拉! - 拉啊! 拉啊!
- Pull! - Pull! Pull!
坚持住!
Hang on!
好啦 幸运的伙计们!
There, my lucky lads!
嗯 刚才真是爽啊
Well, that was refreshing.
干得好 Smith
Well done, Smith.
当然
Of course,
要是我落水了 你们也会来救我的
you'd all do the same for me.
- 哦 是啊 是啊 - 我们当然会的
- Oh, sure, sure. - Of course we would.
- 当然 是啊! - 嗯 我们会的!
- Sure, yes! - Yeah, we would!
绝对地!
Absolutely!
甲板上出了什么麻烦吗?
Trouble on deck?
Ratcliffe长官!
Governor Ratcliffe!
Thomas掉进水里了 长官
Thomas fell overboard, sir.
谢天谢地他又被救回来了
Thank heavens he's been successfully retrieved.
- 干得好 Smith - 谢谢 长官
- Well done, Smith. - Thank you, sir.
不要灰心 大家
Don't lose heart, men.
离我们的新世界已经不远了...
It won't be long before we reach the New World...
记住什么在等待着我们...
And remember what awaits us there...
自由...
Freedom...
繁荣...
prosperity...
我们生命的伟大历程
the adventure of our lives.
你们是全英国最好的船员...
You're the finest crew England has to offer...
没有任何东西... 不论是风是雨
and nothing... not wind nor rain
还是千百个残忍的野蛮人
nor a thousand bloodthirsty savages
能够挡住我们的去路
shall stand in our way.
坚持住 大家!
Carry on, men!
一场激动人心的演说 长官
A stirring oration, sir.
我肯定大家都很受鼓舞!
I'm sure the men were most exhilarated!
希望是这样
Let us hope so.
我需要那班乡巴佬去 帮我挖金子 不是吗?
I'll need those witless peasants to dig up my gold, won't I?
新世界一定棒极了 John
This New World's gonna be great, John.
我要去弄一大堆金子...
I'm gonna get a pile of gold...
盖座大大的房子...
build me a big house...
如果哪个印第安人敢阻止我 我就开枪打死他
and if any Indian tries to stop me, I'll blast him.
你只管关心你的金子好了 Thomas
You just worry about that fortune of yours, Thomas.
那些野蛮人交给我
Leave the savages to me.
你觉得他们会给我们 制造很多麻烦吗?
You think they'll give us much trouble?
Smith会给他们更多
Not as much trouble as Smith'll give them.
# 我们会除去一个印第安人 #
# We'll kill ourselves an Injun #
# 或者可能两个三个 #
# Or maybe two or three #
# 我们是坚定勇敢的 #
# We're stalwart men and bold #
# 维吉尼亚公司人 #
# of the Virginia Company #
你们觉得新世界 将会是怎样的?
What do you suppose the New World will look like?
就像其它的一样 我觉得
Like all the others, I suppose.
我见过几百个新世界 Thomas
I've seen hundreds of new worlds, Thomas.
这个会有什么区别呢?
What could possibly be different about this one?
# 这是荣耀 这是主 这是金子 #
# It's glory, God and gold #
# 也是维吉尼亚公司 #
# And the Virginia Company #
# 规律得像打鼓 #
# Steady as the beating drum #
# 唱歌像松笛 #
# Singing to the cedar flute #
# 四季交替 #
# Seasons go and seasons come #
# 带来玉米 结出水果 #
# Bring the corn and bear the fruit #
# 清甜透明的水 #
# By the waters sweet and clean #
# 养育着有力的鲟鱼 #
# Where the mighty sturgeon lives #
# 种下南瓜 灌溉大豆 #
# Plant the squash and reap the bean #
# 每一寸土地都是母亲所赐 #
# All the Earth our mother gives #
# 哦 情绪高涨 听我们唱歌 #
# Oh, great spirit, hear our song #
# 沿袭着古老的传统 #
# Help us keep the ancient ways #
# 维持着神圣的火焰 #
# Keep the sacred fire strong #
# 一切都已进入我们和谐的生活 #
# Walk in balance all our days #
# 四季交替 #
# Seasons go and seasons come #
# 规律得就像打鼓 #
# steady as the beating drum #
# 从李子到种子到芽再到李子 #
# Plum to seed to bud to plum #
# 规律得像打鼓 #
# Steady as the beating drum #
回家的感觉太好了
It's good to be home.
Masawomecs部落被我们击败了!
The Massawomecks are defeated!
在我们兄弟的帮助下
With the help of our brothers,
我们的部落又安全了
our villages are safe again.
你的回来已经为我们的部落 带来很大的愉快了
Your return has brought much joy to the village.
看看这些笑脸
Look at all the smiling faces.
恩 但是还有一张笑脸我没有看到
Yes, but there's one smiling face I don't see.
我的宝贝女儿呢?
Where is my daughter?
你知道Pocahontas
You know Pocahontas.
她有着她母亲的热情
She has her mother's spirit.
风带她去哪儿 她就会去哪儿
She goes wherever the wind takes her.
Pocahontas啊!
Pocahontas!
你父亲回来了!
Your father's back!
快下来!
Come down here!
他回来了 Flit
He's back, Flit.
跟上 Meeko!
Come on, Meeko!
不! 不要走这边
No! Not that way.
卖弄
Show-off.
Pocahontas啊?
Pocahontas?
Pocahontas! 你还好吗?
Pocahontas! Are you all right?
嗯 你最好没事...
Well, you better be all right...
因为我可不会跳下去救你!
because I'm not coming in after you!
你不觉得我们玩这种游戏...
Don't you think we're getting a...
年纪有点大了吗?
a little old for these games?
帮我把船翻过来
Help me turn this thing over.
你在那上面做什么?
What were you doing up there?
思考 Meeko!
Thinking. Meeko!
又是关于那个梦? 你还没有完全想出来吗?
About the dream again? Have you figured it out yet?
我知道那一定暗示着什么东西
I know it means something.
但就是不知道具体是什么
I just don't know what.
你应该向你父亲问问这件事
You should ask your father about it.
也许是该问问他
Maybe I should.
上来 Flit
Come on, Flit.
不要再到处乱玩 我们得回去了
Quit playing around. We have to get back.
...面对着一个坚定的敌人
...faced a determined enemy.
战斗从太阳刚刚升起
The battle lasted from the rising of the sun
一直持续到夜幕降临
until the evening shadows fell.
我们的战士勇往直前
Our warriors fought with courage,
但是还没人像Kocoum这般勇敢...
but none as bravely as Kocoum...
因为他战斗像熊一样的凶猛
for he attacked with the fierce strength of the bear.
他的实际行动证明了他就是我们中最棒的...
He has proven himself to be the greatest of warriors...
- 哦 他可真帅啊! - 我特别喜欢他的微笑
- Oh, he is so handsome! - I especially love his smile.
消灭每一个阻挡他的敌人
Destroying every enemy in his path.
今晚 我们要为他举行盛宴
Tonight we will feast in his honour.
- 宝贝女儿 - 一切安好 父亲
- My daughter. - Wing-gap-o, Father.
见到你就是我最大的快乐
Seeing you gives me great joy.
真高兴您平安回家
I'm so glad you've come home safely.
跟我来 我有太多话要对你说
Come with me. We have much to talk about.
我要听听你做的每一件事情
I want to hear everything you've been doing.
父亲 好几个晚上...
Father, for many nights now...
我都做到同一个奇怪的梦
I've been having a very strange dream.
我想那是要告诉我 什么事将要发生
I think it's telling me something's about to happen.
一件激动人心的事
Something exciting.
没错 是有一件激动人心的事即将发生
Yes, something exciting is about to happen.
真的吗? 那是什么?
Really? What is it?
Kocoum已经向我提亲 他要和你结婚
Kocoum has asked to seek your hand in marriage.
嫁给Kocoum?
Marry Kocoum?
我告诉他那会让我心情飞扬
I told him it would make my heart soar.
但是 他太... 严肃了
But he's so... serious.
我的女儿 Kocoum将会是一个好丈夫
My daughter, Kocoum will make a fine husband.
他既忠诚又强壮 会用结实的墙壁为你建造...
He is loyal and strong and will build you a good house...
一所好房子
with sturdy walls.
和他在一起 你会很安全
With him, you will be safe from harm.
父亲 我想我的梦 正在指引我走向另一条路
Father, I think my dream is pointing me down another path.
这对你来说是一条正确的路
This is the right path for you.
但是为什么我就没有选择的...
But why can't I choose...
Pocahontas 跟我来
Pocahontas, come with me.
你是酋长的女儿
You are the daughter of the chief.
是该你履行责任的时候了
It is time to take your place among our people.
即使山野小溪...
Even the wild mountain stream...
有一天也会流进大河
must someday join the big river.
# 当大河截断他的路 #
# As the river cuts his path #
# 虽然大河骄傲和强壮 #
# Though the river's proud and strong #
# 他也会选择一段最平坦的路程 #
# He will choose the smoothest course #
这就是为什么 大河能活得那么久
That's why rivers live so long.
# 他们那么稳定 #
# They're steady #
# 稳定得就像打鼓 #
# As the steady beating drum #
你母亲在我们的婚礼上戴着这个
Your mother wore this for our wedding.
看见你亲手戴上是她的梦想
It was her dream to see you wear it at your own.
很配你
It suits you.
他想让我稳定
He wants me to be steady
就像河一样
like the river.
但是他根本就不稳定
But it's not steady at all.
# 我之所以喜欢大河是因为... #
# What I love most about rivers... #
# 你没办法两次走进同一条河 #
# is you can't step in the same river twice #
# 河水始终在不停地变化 #
# The water's always changing #
# 不断地流动 #
# always flowing #
# 但是人 我猜 不能那样活着 #
# But people, I guess can't live like that. #
# 我们都必须付出代价 #
# We all must pay a price #
# 为了安全 我们甚至失去了去了解 #
# To be safe we lose our chance of ever knowing #
# 河湾附近的景色的机会 #
# What's around the river bend #
# 就在河湾附近等待? #
# Waiting just around the river bend? #
# 让我再看一次 #
# I look once more just #
# 就在河湾附近 #
# around the river bend #
# 超越了海岸 #
# Beyond the shore #
# 那里有海鸥自由飞翔 #
# where the gulls fly free #
# 不知道为了什么 #
# Don't know what for #
# 我梦到的那天可能会到来 #
# What I dream the day might send #
# 就在河湾附近 #
# Just around the river bend #
# 为了我 #
# For me #
# 为我而来 #
# Coming for me #
# 我感觉到它就在那儿 树的那边 #
# I feel it there beyond those trees #
# 也在这些水帘背后 #
# or right behind these waterfalls #
# 我能忽视远处的鼓声吗 #
# Can I ignore that sound of distant drumming #
# 为了一个英俊可靠的丈夫 #
# For a handsome sturdy husband #
# 他将为我建造漂亮结实的墙壁 #
# who builds handsome, sturdy walls #
# 然后再也不去想有事将要发生 #
# And never dreams that something might be coming #
# 就在河湾附近 #
# Just around the river bend #
# 让我再看一次 #
# I look once more #
# 就在河湾附近 #
# just around the river bend #
# 超越了海岸 #
# Beyond the shore #
# 那里就是大海 #
# Somewhere past the sea #
# 不知道为了什么 #
# Don't know what for #
# 为什么我的梦总是那么超前 #
# Why do all my dreams extend #
# 就在河湾附近 #
# Just around the river bend #
# 我是不是应该选择最平滑的路程 #
# Should I choose the smoothest course #
# 稳定得就像打鼓一样? #
# Steady as the beating drum #
# 我是不是应该嫁给Kocoum?
# Should I marry Kocoum?
# 我所有的梦都了结了 #
# Is all my dreaming at an end #
# 或者你还在 #
# Or do you still #
# 等着我 拖梦人? #
# Wait for me Dream giver? #
# 就在河湾 #
# Just around the river #
# 附近? #
# bend? #
是我的Pocahontas吗?
Is that my Pocahontas?
Willow奶奶 我有话对你说
Grandmother Willow, I need to talk to you.
早上好 孩子
Good morning, child.
我知道你今天会来
I was hoping you'd visit today.
哦! 你母亲的项链!
Oh! Why, your mother's necklace!
这就是我打算和你说的
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
我父亲想把我嫁给Kocoum
My father wants me to marry Kocoum.
Kocoum? 但是他太严肃了
Kocoum? But he's so serious.
我知道 我父亲 认为这是我应该走的路
I know. My father thinks it's the right path for me.
但是最近 我总 在做一个梦 我想它...
But lately, I've been having this dream and I think it's...
哦 一个梦! 让我们来听听!
Oh, a dream! Let's hear all about it.
安静!
Quiet!
现在 孩子 你开始说吧
Now, child, you were saying.
恩 我在树林里跑...
Well, I'm running through the woods...
就在我前方出现了 一个箭头
and then, right there in front of me, is an arrow.
当我去看时 它就开始旋转
As I look at it, it starts to spin.
旋转的箭头? 真不寻常
A spinning arrow. How unusual.
是的 它旋转得 越来越快 越来越快
Yes. It spins faster and faster and faster
直到突然间... 停止了
until suddenly... it stops.
恩 看起来这个旋转的箭头...
Well, it seems to me this spinning arrow...
正在指示你应该走的路
is pointing you down your path.
但是 Willow奶奶 我的路到底在哪?
But, Grandmother Willow, what is my path?
我该怎样去找到它?
How am I ever going to find it?
你母亲问了我同样一个问题
Your mother asked me the very same question.
她也问了? 那你怎么回答她的?
She did? What did you tell her?
我让她去聆听
I told her to listen.
你周围都是生灵 孩子
All around you are spirits, child.
它们生活在泥土里 水里 天上
They live in the earth, the water, the sky.
如果你仔细去聆听 它们会指引你的
If you listen, they will guide you.
我听到风了
I hear the wind.
恩 它告诉你什么?
Yes. What is it telling you?
我不懂
I don't understand.
# 你会明白的 #
# You will understand #
# 用心去聆听 #
# Listen with your heart #
# 你会明白的 #
# You will understand #
# 让它来指引你 #
# Let it break upon you #
# 就像波浪打在沙滩上 #
# Like a wave upon the sand #
它说什么东西来了
It's saying something's coming.
奇怪的云彩?
Strange clouds?
# 用心去聆听 #
# Listen with your heart #
# 你会明白的 #
# You will understand #
你看到了什么?
What do you see?
云彩
Clouds.
奇怪的云彩
Strange clouds.
看看这儿 Wiggins...
Look at it, Wiggins...
一个堆满金子的新世界...
An entire new world chock full of gold...
正等着我
just waiting for me.
还有许多惊险在等着我们 对吗 Percy?
And scores of adventures waiting for us. Right, Percy?
你觉得我们会遇到那些野蛮人吗?
Do you think we'll meet some savages?
如果遇上了 我们肯定会给他们...
If we do, we shall be sure...
一个合适的英国式问候
to give them a proper English greeting.
哦! 礼品篮!
Ooh! gift baskets!
哦 不! 他们被抬举得太高了
Oh, no! And he came so highly recommended.
太完美了 长官
It's perfect, Governor.
水足够深 我们可以直接把船拖到岸边
The water's deep enough. We can pull right up to shore.
你好啊 Percy
Hey there, Percy.
非常好 下令去吧
Very well, then. Give the order.
已经完成 长官
Already done, sir.
我已经把船员集合好了 他们正准备出发
I've got a crew assembled and they're ready to go.
至于那些土著...
About the natives...
我希望你确定一下...
I'm counting on you to make sure...
那些肮脏的野蛮人 不要打扰我们的工作
those filthy heathens don't disrupt our mission.
如果他们是我曾经 对付过的那种野蛮人
Well, if they're anything like the savages I've fought before,
没有我不能处理的
it's nothing I can't handle.
- 好 那就行了 Smith - 乖孩子
- Right. That'll be all, Smith. - There's a good man.
再见 Percy
See you, Percy.
那些人喜欢Smith 是不是?
The men like Smith, don't they?
我从来都不是... 一个受欢迎的人
I've never been... a popular man.
我喜欢你
I like you.
不要以为我不知道...
And don't think I don't know...
那些混蛋在宫廷里是怎么说我的
what those back stabbers at court say about me.
哦 是啊 整场对话关于一个
Oh, yes, all that talk about
可怜的想进入上流社会的人 在每一件事上总是失败...
being a pathetic social climber who's failed at everything...
我很清楚地知道这是我 最后一次为荣誉而战的机会
I'm very well aware that this is my last chance for glory.
你记住今天我所说的 Wiggins.
But mark my words, Wiggins.
当詹姆士国王看到 那些村夫挖来的金子...
When King James sees the gold these peasants unearth...
成功最终会是我的
success will be mine at last.
醒醒! 动起来!
Wake up! Shake a leg!
真是难以置信!
It's incredible!
这些全都是我们的啦
And it's all ours.
我从来没有见过这样的东西
I've never seen anything like it.
就算它看上去像Ratcliffe的灯笼裤我也不管 我现在只想...
It could look like Ratcliffe's knickers, for all I care...
尽快离开这艘发臭的烂船
just as long as I get off this stinkin' boat.
跟上来 伙计们
Come on, men.
我们大老远来不是为了就看看它的
We didn't come all this way just to look at it.
拉紧 伙计们 拉紧 牢牢地! 牢牢地! 抓住! 够远了
Keep it taut, lads. Keep it taut. Steady! Steady! Hold up! That's far enough.
好啦... 将她绑好
All right... now. Tie her off.
接着 John 系牢这一端
Here, John, tie off this end.
John啊? John啊?
John? John?
你在那上面干什么呢?
What are you doing up there?
找一个更好的视野
Getting a better look.
你看起来很奇怪
You're a strange-looking fellow.
你饿了吗?
Are you hungry?
拿去 啊 是饼干
Here you go. Ah, it's a biscuit.
这是食物 恩 算是吧
It's food. Well, sort of.
你喜欢 恩?
You like it, eh?
试着连续吃上四个月
Well, try eating it for four months straight.
那后面有你的朋友?
You got a friend back there?
嗨! 什么...这是什么? 当心
Hey! Wh... What? Watch out.
什么? 不... 别这样... 呃 当心
What? Get... No, get... Uh, look out.
John 你最好还是下来!
John, you better get down here!
长官要上岸了
The governor's coming ashore.
好 好 我这就走了
All right. All right. I'm leaving.
你看到他们的皮肤吗? 他们像狗一样脸上长毛
Did you see their skin? They have hair on their faces like dogs.
兄弟们 我们必须仔细了解一下这些来客
My brothers, we must know more about these visitors.
Kekata 你看到什么?
Kekata, what do you see?
他们并不是像我们这样的人...
These are not men like us...
而是有着能够像太阳一样发光的躯体的怪物...
but strange beasts with bodies that shine like the sun...
他们有着能够喷射火和雷的武器
and weapons that spout fire and thunder.
他们巡游着土地 就像贪婪的恶狼...
They prowl the Earth like ravenous wolves...
用他们的方式来毁灭一切
consuming everything in their path.
Great Powhatan 我要带领我们的战士们
Great Powhatan, I will lead our warriors
去河边去战斗
to the river and attack.
我们要摧毁这些侵略者...
We will destroy these invaders...
就像我们摧毁Masawomecs部落那样
the way we destroyed the Massawomecks.
Kocoum 在那场战役中 我们知道如何和敌人作战...
Kocoum, in that battle we knew how to fight our enemy...
但是这些白人我们并不了解
But these pale visitors are strange to us.
带一些人去河边监视他们
Take some men to the river to observe them.
希望他们不要准备在这儿逗留
Let us hope they do not intend to stay.
我这里宣布这块土地 还有这里所有的财富...
I hereby claim this land and all its riches...
以最高权威詹姆士国王的名义...
in the name of His Majesty King James the First...
命名为詹姆斯镇
and do so name this settlement Jamestown.
哦也! 哦也! 精彩的演说 长官!
Bravo! Bravo! Beautifully spoken, sir!
快点 Percy
Hurry now, Percy.
我们得为新世界而尽快清洗干净
We must be all squeaky clean for the New World.
Smith船长
Captain Smith,
看来我选择了一个 完美的露营地 恩?
it appears I've selected the perfect location, eh?
没有看到一个野蛮人
Not a savage in sight.
只是我们还没有看到他们...
Just because we don't see them...
并不代表他们不在 长官
doesn't mean they're not out there, sir.
好 那么也许你应该 向前去观察一下...
Well, then perhaps you should venture forth...
弄清楚他们的行踪 嗯?
and determine their whereabouts, hmm?
如果这儿有印第安人的话 我会发现他们的
If there are any Indians out there, I'll find them.
现在 大家 开始干活
Now, gentlemen, to work.
- 你们这些人 去把船上的东西卸下来 - 是 先生
- You men, get the ship unloaded. - Right, sir.
你们去建造堡垒
You men, build the fort.
剩下的 拿出你们的铲子来!
The rest of you, break out the shovels!
可以开挖了!
It's time to start digging!
- 挖? - 挖?
- Digging? - Digging?
当然啦!
Why, of course!
不要忘记那些 西班牙人发现了什么...
Let's not forget what the Spanish found...
在他们来到新世界之后
when they came to the New World.
金子! 满山的金子
Gold! Mountains of it.
啊 没几年 他们就将新世界掠夺一空...
Why, for years they've been ravaging the New World...
拿走了所有的宝贵资源...
of its most precious resources...
但是现在...
but now...
该轮到我们了
it's our turn.
# 金子做的Contez #
# The gold of Cortez #
# 珠宝镶嵌的Pizarro #
# The jewels of Pizarro #
# 在明天这个时候 #
# Will seem like mere trinkets #
# 看起来就会是小玩意 #
# by this time tomorrow #
# 我们在这儿找到的金子 #
# The gold we find here #
# 将会让它们不值一提 #
# will dwarf them by far #
# 哦 使出全力 孩子们 #
# Oh, with all you got in ya, boys #
# 开垦维吉尼亚 孩子们 #
# Dig up Virginia, boys #
# 挖吧 孩子们 #
# Mine, boys #
# 挖开每一座山脉
# Mine every mountain
# 挖吧 孩子们 #
# And dig, boys #
# 挖到最后一点 #
# Dig 'til you drop #
# 快挖吧 孩子们 #
# Grab a pick, boys #
# 快 孩子们 #
# Quick, boys #
# 推进你的铲子 #
# Shove in a shovel #
# 去挖掘那些可爱的小石头 #
# Uncover those loverly pebbles #
# 它们闪闪发光 #
# that sparkle and shine #
# 它们就是金子 #
# It's gold #
# 它们是我的 #
# and it's mine #
# 我的 #
# Mine, #
# mine #
# 挖啊 努力地挖 #
# Dig and dig and diggety dig #
# 挖啊 挖 努力地挖 #
# And dig and dig and diggety dig #
# 哦 我真是爱死它了 #
# Ooh, how I love it. #
# 轻而易举得来的财富 #
# Riches for cheap. #
# 这儿会有很多很多 #
# There'll be heaps of it. #
# 我就站在它的顶端 #
# And I'll be on top of the heap. #
# 努力地挖 #
# Diggety, diggety, dig #
# 我的敌人都见鬼去吧 #
# My rivals back home #
# 并不是我怀恨 #
# It's not that I'm bitter. #
# 只要想想他们怎样地忸怩 #
# But think how they'll squirm #
# 当看到我闪闪发光 #
# when they see how I glitter #
# 宫廷里的女士们 #
# The ladies at court #
# 心里将会紧张不已 #
# will be all a-twitter #
# 国王将会奖赏我 #
# The king will reward me #
# 他会授予我爵位...不! #
# He'll knight me... No! #
# 让位给我 #
# lord me #
# 这是我的! #
# It's mine! #
# 我的 我的 为了憧憬的未来 #
# Mine, Mine for the taking.
# 这是我的 孩子们 给我把金子挖出来! #
# It's mine, boys. Mine me that gold! #
# 把那些金块挖出来 #
# With those nuggets dug #
# 我将被授予荣耀 #
# It's glory they'll gimme #
# 我亲爱的朋友詹姆士国王 #
# My dear friend King Jimmy #
# 将会给我建造一座圣殿 #
# will probably build me a shrine #
# 在所有这些金子 #
# When all of the gold #
# 都挖出来后 #
# Is mined #
# 挖啊 挖 努力地挖 #
# Dig and dig and diggety dig #
# 我一生所追求的 #
# All of my life I have searched #
# 就是这样一块土地 #
# for a land like this one #
# 一个狂野刺激的国度 #
# A wilder, more challenging country #
# 我没法设计 #
# I couldn't design #
# 许多危险在等待 #
# Hundreds of dangers await #
# 我不打算错过任何一个 #
# and I don't plan to miss one #
# 在一片我可以认领的土地 #
# In a land I can claim. #
# 一片我可以驯服的土地 #
# A land I can tame. #
# 最伟大的历险是我的 #
# The greatest adventure is mine. #
# 努力工作 伙计们 #
# Keep on working, lads. #
# 不要偷懒 伙计们 #
# Don't be shirking, lads. #
# 挖啊 孩子们 挖啊 #
# Mine, boys, mine. #
# 挖啊 #
# Mine #
# 我的 #
# Me #
# 金子 挖啊 挖 #
# that gold. Dig, dig #
# 努力地挖 #
# and diggety. #
# 美丽的金子 挖啊 #
# Beautiful gold Dig, #
# 为了那些金子 #
# dig for that gold #
# 这是我的领地 我的领地 #
# Make this island my land #
# 让土堆变得更大 孩子们 #
# Make the mounds big, boys. #
# 我也想帮你们挖 孩子们 #
# I'd help you to dig, boys. #
# 但是我肌肉抽搐 #
# But I've got this crick in me spine. #
# 我们看到的这片土地 #
# This land we behold #
# 美丽得无法形容 #
# This beauty untold #
# 人可以勇敢 #
# A man can be bold #
# 这些都可以拿来卖 #
# It all can be sold #
# 这些金子 #
# The gold #
# 是 #
# Is #
# 我的 #
# Mine #
# 我的 挖啊 挖 #
# Is mine And dig and dig #
# 努力地挖 #
# and diggety dig #
# 这是我的 #
# It's mine. #
不! 等等! 请不要走...
No! Wait! Please...
不要走!
Please!
不要跑开
Don't run off.
没事的
It's all right.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
来 让我扶你上来
Here. Let me help you out of there.
你听不懂我所说的 是吗?
You don't understand a word I'm saying, do you?
没关系
It's all right.
# 用心去聆听 #
# Listen with your heart #
# 你会明白的 #
# You will understand #
# 让它来指引你 #
# Let it break upon you #
# 就像波浪打在沙滩上 #
# Like a wave upon the sand #
你是谁?
Who are you?
# 用心去聆听 #
# Listen with your heart #
# 你会明白的 #
# You will understand #
我叫Pocahontas
Pocahontas.
什么? 你刚才说什么?
What? What did you say?
我的名字叫Pocahontas
My name is Pocahontas.
我是John Smith
I'm John Smith.
就在这样 继续挖 大家
That's it. Keep at it, men.
继续挖啊 一定就在这儿某个地方
Keep digging. It's got to be here somewhere.
下面山脊上他们有30多个人
There's 30 more of them down by the ridge.
就是说总共有百来个人!
That makes more than a hundred!
找到什么了吗?
Anything yet?
除了石头和泥土 什么都没有 长官
Nothing but rocks and dirt, sir.
我们到底还要挖多久 长官?
Um, how long are we going to keep digging like this, sir?
对阿! 我们整天整夜没完没了地挖
Aye! We're slaving away, busting our backs day and night.
为了国王 为了国家 我明白 我明白
For king and country. I know, I know.
我知道你们很疲倦
And I share your fatigue.
Wiggins啊!
Wiggins!
来啦!
Coming!
处理掉这个
Dispose of this.
谁是好狗狗?
Who's a good doggy?
接住 乖孩子!
Fetch, boy!
水手们! 有埋伏! 武装起来!
Savages! It's an ambush! Arm yourselves!
跑!
Run!
武装起来!
Arm yourselves!
每个人都带上一把步枪!
Make sure every man has a musket.
射击!
Shoot!
打他们 你个笨蛋!
Them, you idiot!
我正需要他 那个该死的Smith去哪儿了?
Where's that blasted Smith when I need him?
Namontack啊!
Namontack!
快回部落去!
Back to the village!
闭嘴 闭嘴 你们这些笨蛋!
Shut up. Shut up, you fools!
他们会回来的
They'll be back.
所有人都回营地去
Everyone, back to camp.
把所有加农炮都弄上岸来
Get the rest of the cannons ashore
立刻完成堡垒的修建工作!
and finish building the fort!
是的 长官!
Aye, Governor!
还有你...
And you...
好好学学怎么用那个玩意吧
Learn to use that thing properly.
不会玩枪就不是男人
A man's not a man unless he knows how to shoot.
那些怪物侵入了我们的海岸...
These beasts invade our shores...
然后现在又...
and now this...
这个伤口对我来说太奇怪了
This wound is strange to me.
我们要和这些敌人战斗...
We will fight this enemy...
但是我们不能独自去做
but we cannot do it alone.
Kocoum 送信给我们的每一个部落
Kocoum, send messengers to every village in our nation.
我们要召集我们的兄弟们一起去战斗
We will call on our brothers to help us fight.
这些白人非常危险!
These white men are dangerous!
任何人都不许接近他们
No one is to go near them.
这个叫做头盔
It's called a helmet.
头盔
Helmet.
那么 恩...这是什么河啊?
So, uh... what river is this?
Quyukhanic河
Quyukhanic.
你的名字也很不同寻常
You have the most unusual names here.
Chicahomeni Quyu... 还是Quyukhanic
Chicahomeni Quyu...Quyukhanic
是Pocahontas
Pocahontas.
你同样有着最不同寻常的名字
You have the most unusual name too.
John Smith啊
John Smith.
这个永不知足的小家伙是你的朋友吗?
Is this bottomless pit a friend of yours?
Meeko啊!
Meeko!
嗯 你好吗 Meeko?
Well, how do you do, Meeko?
没什么 这只是一个握手罢了
It's all right. It's just a handshake.
来 让我来教你
Here, let me show you.
不会发生什么吧
Nothing's happening.
呃 不 不 我只要你伸出手来
Uh, no, no. I need your hand first.
这是问好的方式
It's how we say hello.
这是我们问好的方式
This is how we say hello.
然后这是我们怎样说再见
And how we say goodbye.
我更喜欢问好
I like hello better.
对了 我记得你
Yeah, I remember you.
Flit只是不喜欢陌生人
Flit just doesn't like strangers.
但是 我已经不是陌生人了
Well, I'm not a stranger any more.
顽固的小家伙 是不是?
Stubborn little fellow, isn't he?
确实有些
Very stubborn.
Meeko! 回到这儿来
Meeko! come back here.
别当心 他弄不坏的
Don't worry. He can't hurt it.
嗨! 你在干什么?
Hey! What are you doing?
Meeko 把它拿回来!
Meeko, bring that back!
不 没事 给它吧
N-No, it's all right. He can keep it.
就当作见面礼吧
Call it a gift.
那是什么?
What was that?
- 我的指南针 - 指南针?
- My compass. - Compass?
当你迷路的时候 它会告诉你怎么走
It tells you how to find your way when you get lost.
但是没事 回到伦敦我会买一个新的
But it's all right. I'll get another one in London.
伦敦? 那是你的部落吗?
London? Is that your village?
是的 一个非常大的部落
Yes. It's a very big village.
那是怎样的?
What's it like?
恩 那儿有车来车往的街道...
Well, it's got streets filled with carriages...
跨越河流的大桥...
bridges over the rivers...
还有树一般高的建筑
and buildings as tall as trees.
我想去看看那些东西
I'd like to see those things.
- 你会的 - 怎样?
- You will. - How?
我们将在这儿建造那些东西
We're going to build them here.
我们会教你们的人 怎样合理利用土地
We'll show your people how to use this land properly,
怎样最好地利用它
how to make the most of it.
最好地利用它?
Make the most of it?
对 我们会修建 公路和漂亮的房屋...
Yes. We'll build roads and decent houses and...
我们的房子也很好
Our houses are fine.
你那样想只是因为 你不知道更好的
You think that only because you don't know any better.
等等 不要那么...
W-Wait a minute. Don't take it tha...
嗨 嗨! 等等!
Hey. Hey! Wait!
等等! 我们还能教你们更多
Wa-Wait! There's so much we can teach you.
我们要改变全世界的野蛮的生活
We've improved the lives of savages all over the world.
野蛮的?!
Savages?!
呃 不是说你野蛮
Uh, not that you're a savage.
- 那就是我们的人民 - 不
- Just my people. - No.
听着 那不是我想说的
Listen. That's not what I meant.
- 让我来解释 - 让我走!
- Let me explain. - Let go!
不 我不会让你离开的
No, I'm not letting you leave.
恩 不要那样子
Look, don't do this.
野蛮仅仅是一个词而已 你明白吗?
Savage is just a word, uh, you know?
一个术语... 来形容那些未开化的人
A term... for people who are uncivilized.
就像我
Like me.
恩 我说的未开化...
Well, when I say uncivilized...
是指... 指...
what I mean is... is...
你是指...和你不一样
What you mean is... not like you.
# 你觉得我是一个无知的野蛮人 #
# You think I'm an ignorant savage #
# 你去过那么多地方 #
# And you've been so many places #
# 我想那应该是这样 #
# I guess it must be so #
# 但是仍然 我不明白 #
# But still I cannot see #
# 如果野蛮人都是我 #
# If the savage one is me #
# 怎么还会有那么多的东西 #
# How can there be so much #
# 你不知道? #
# that you don't know? #
# 你不知道 #
# You don't know #
# 你认为你所登陆的土地都是你的 #
# You think you own whatever land you land on #
# 大地只是一个没有生命的东西 #
# The Earth is just a dead thing you can claim #
# 但是我知道每一块石头 每一棵树木每一个生灵 #
# But I know every rock and tree and creature #
# 都有它的生命 有它的灵魂 #
# Has a life, has a spirit #
# 有它的名字 #
# Has a name #
# 你认为只有像你那样 #
# You think the only people who are people #
# 看问题和想问题的人 才是真正的人 #
# Are the people who look and think like you #
# 但是如果你沿着一个陌生人的足迹走下去 #
# But if you walk the footsteps of a stranger #
# 你会学到 #
# You'll learn things #
# 你从来不知道的事情 你从来不知道的事情 #
# you never knew you never knew #
# 你曾经听到过野狼 #
# Have you ever heard the wolf #
# 对着蓝色天空里的明月嚎叫 #
# cry to the blue corn moon #
# 或者问过野猫 为什么它要呲牙咆哮吗? #
# Or asked the grinning bobcat why he grinned?
# 你能和着大山的声音 #
# Can you sing with #
# 一起唱歌吗? #
# all the voices of the mountain? #
# 你能用风的颜色 #
# Can you paint with #
# 来绘画吗? #
# all the colours of the wind? #
# 你能用风的颜色 #
# Can you paint with all the colours #
# 来绘画吗? #
# Of the wind? #
# 来沿着寂寞的林间小路 #
# Come run the hidden pine trails #
# 奔跑 #
# of the forest #
# 来尝尝大地 #
# Come taste the sun #
# 甜美的浆果 #
# sweet berries of the Earth #
# 来在你周围 富饶的土地上打滚 #
# Come roll in all the riches all around you #
# 只是 不要去计较是否值得 #
# And for once never wonder what they're worth
# 暴风雨和河流 #
# The rainstorm and the river #
# 是我的兄弟 #
# are my brothers #
# 苍鹭和水獭 #
# The heron and the otter #
# 是我的朋友 #
# are my friends #
# 我们彼此都息息相关 #
# And we are all connected to each other #
# 周而复始永不停息 #
# In a circle In a hoop that never ends #
# 枫树能 #
# How high #
# 长得多么的高? #
# does the sycamore grow? #
# 如果你把它砍了 #
# If you cut it down #
# 你将永远不会知道 #
# then you'll never know #
# 你将永远 #
# And you'll never #
# 不会听到野狼嚎叫 #
# hear the wolf cry #
# 对着蓝色天空里的明月 #
# to the blue corn moon #
# 不管我们是白色 还是棕色的皮肤 #
# For whether we are white or copper-skinned #
# 我们需要和着
# We need to sing with
# 大山的声音来歌唱 #
# all the voices of the mountain #
# 我们需要用 #
# We need to paint with #
# 风的颜色来绘画 #
# all the colours of the wind #
# 你会拥有大地 仍然 #
# You can own the Earth and still #
# 所有你将拥有的是大地直到 #
# All you'll own is earth until #
# 你能够 #
# You can paint #
# 用风的颜色 #
# With all the colours #
# 来绘画 #
# Of the wind. #
怎么了?
What is it?
鼓声 它意味着麻烦
The drums. They mean trouble.
我不能再待在这儿了
I shouldn't be here.
- 我想再见到你 - 我不能
- I want to see you again. - I can't.
- 求你 不要离开 - 我很抱歉
- Please, don't leave. - I'm sorry.
我必须得走了
I have to go.
好的! 已经准备好举起来了!
All right! This one's ready to hoist!
- 每边各两个人 - 准备好了吗? 推!
- Two on each side. - Ready now? Push!
小心 滑掉了
Watch it. It's slippery.
加油啊 伙计们 这只是一块篱笆
Come on, lads. It's only a little picket fence.
- 稳住! 稳住! - 这就行了
- Steady! Steady! - There you go.
这会把一切挡在外面 恩 John?
That'll keep everything out, eh, John?
有什么不妥吗 John?
Something wrong, John?
什么?
What?
这几天你都异常地平静
You've been awfully quiet the last few days.
哦 他只是觉得 他错过了所有的行动
Oh, he's just mad that he missed all the action.
啊 不用着急 John
Ah, don't worry, John.
你会有机会去对付 那些印第安人的
You'll get your chance to deal with the Indians.
对 我们会对付他们的...
Yeah, we'll take care of them...
就像上次那样 恩 大伙?
like we did last time, eh, mates?
# 我们会打死一个印第安人 #
# We shot ourselves an Injun #
# 或许两个三个 #
# or maybe two or three #
好了 你个疯子 快去做事!
All right, you howling nutter, get to work!
不要这样 Ben 只是开开玩笑而已
Come on, Ben. It's just a little fun.
哦 当然! 我们有很多乐趣 不是吗?
Oh, sure! We're having loads of fun, right?
看看我们 没有金子 没有食物
Look at us. No gold, no food.
那个Ratcliffe还整天 坐在他的帐篷里...
While Ratcliffe sits up in his tent all day...
快活得像个蛤蛎
happy as a clam.
我烦死了!
I am doomed!
现在我已经应该在金子里打滚了...
I should be wallowing in riches by now...
而我却还没有找到一点点金疙瘩!
and I haven't found as much as a speck!
想想 想想!
Think. Think!
应该就在这附近的某个地方
It's got to be around here somewhere.
到底应该在哪儿呢?
Where could it be?
我已经挖掘过森林和山丘
I've mined the forests and the hills
还有沼泽... 什么都没有!
and the swamps... And nothing!
为什么我找不到? 我到底忽略了哪里?
Why can't I find it? What am I overlooking?
我... 我...
I... I...
我自己做的
I made it myself.
那样看起来很傻...
Take that silly...
肯定是的! 那些印第安人
Of course! The Indians.
Wiggins 你觉得为什么...
Wiggins, why do you think...
那些野蛮人要袭击我们?
those insolent heathens attacked us?
因为我们侵入了他们的地盘
Because we invaded their land
砍了他们的树 挖了他们的土地?
and cut down their trees and dug up their earth?
是金子! 他们拥有金子...
It's the gold! They have it...
他们不愿意我们把它带走
and they don't want us to take it from them.
那么 我就只好用武力了 不是吗?
Well, I'll just have to take it by force, then, won't I?
你们这些人! Smith船长去哪儿了?
You there! Where's Captain Smith?
恩 他走了
Well, he's gone.
对 一定是你唱歌把他吓跑了
Aye. Your singing must have scared them off.
那么 看在上帝的份上 把他找来!
Well, then go get him, for heaven's sake!
要是我们遇到印第安人怎么办?
What if we run into the Indians?
那就用枪来对付他们
That's what guns are for.
马上武装起来出发!
Now arm yourselves and get moving!
Pocahontas啊
Pocahontas.
你应该待在部落里
You should be inside the village.
我们会没事的
We'll be all right.
我们正在为战士们准备食物
We're gathering food for when the warriors arrive.
不要走太远了
Don't go far.
现在不是到处乱跑的时候
Now is not the time to be running off.
是的 父亲
Yes, Father.
当我看到你戴着那串项链...
When I see you wear that necklace...
你就像你母亲一样
you look just like your mother.
我想她
I miss her.
但她仍然和我们在一起
But she is still with us.
无论何时风吹过树林...
Whenever the wind moves through the trees...
我就感觉到她的存在
I feel her presence.
我们的人民向她祈祷智慧和力量
Our people looked to her for wisdom and strength.
有一天 他们也会向你祈祷
Someday, they will look to you as well.
我会感到无限荣耀
I would be honoured by that.
你不应该单独待在这儿
You shouldn't be out here alone.
我会叫Kocoum过来的
I'll send for Kocoum.
好了 到底怎么回事?
All right. What is it?
- 什么? - 你隐瞒着什么东西
- What? - You're hiding something.
我没有隐瞒任何东西
I'm not hiding anything.
Pocahontas 你可以告诉我 我发誓
Pocahontas, you can tell me. I promise
我不会告诉任何人的... Pocahontas 看!
I won't tell anyone... Pocahontas, look!
这是他们其中一个! 我要去找...
It's one of them! I'm going to get...
你在这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
我必须要再见你一次
I had to see you again.
Pocahontas啊!
Pocahontas!
求你! 不要说任何事
Please! Don't say anything.
快! 这边!
Quick! this way!
- 但是... - Nakoma
- But... - Nakoma.
Pocahontas呢?
Where is Pocahontas?
我... 我没有看到她
I... I haven't seen her.
Pocahontas不能再到处乱跑了
Pocahontas can't keep running off.
外面很危险
It's dangerous out there.
告诉她这些 她听你的话
Tell her that. She listens to you.
嗨! 她当然听我的
Huh! Sure she does.
这个地方实在太难以置信了
This place is incredible.
想想我们长途跋涉...
And to think we came all this way...
只是为了挖金子
just to dig it up for gold.
金子?
Gold?
- 嗨 Meeko - 什么是金子?
- Hey, Meeko. - What's gold?
你也许知道 就是... 黄黄的
You know, it's, uh... it's, it's yellow.
从地里头挖出来的 非常宝贵
It comes out of the ground. It's really valuable.
哦! 这个 我们这儿有很多
Oh! Here, we have lots of it.
金子
Gold.
不 不! 金子是这个
No No! Gold is this.
这附近没有这样的东西
There's nothing like that around here.
- 没有金子? - 至少我没见过
- No gold? - Not that I've seen.
这一趟算是白跑了
All this way for nothing.
那些孩子们将会大吃一惊的
Well, those boys are in for a big surprise.
- 他们会离开吗? - 其中一些可能会
- Will they leave? - Some of them might.
你会回家吗?
Will you go home?
我没什么家可回的
Well, it's not like I have much of a home to go back to.
我从来没有 真正属于过任何地方
I've never really belonged anywhere.
你可以属于这儿
You could belong here.
那是什么?!
What was that?!
你看到什么了吗?
Did you see something?
不 不 我只是...我...
No. No. I just, uh... I...
我没有看到任何东西 是不是?
I didn't see anything, did I?
再看一次
Look again.
# 让它来指引你 #
# Let it break upon you #
# 就像波浪打在沙滩上 #
# Like a wave upon the sand #
你好 John Smith
Hello, John Smith.
Pocahontas 那棵树在和我说话
Pocahontas, that tree is talking to me.
那么你就应该回答
Then you should talk back.
不要害怕 年轻人
Don't be frightened, young man.
我的树皮比我咬的更痛
My bark is worse than my bite.
说点什么
Say something.
对一棵树应该说些什么?
What do you say to a tree?
任何你想说的
Anything you want.
那么 恩...
So, uh...
靠近些 John Smith
Come closer, John Smith.
他有一个善良的灵魂
He has a good soul.
他也很帅气!
And he's handsome too!
- 哦 我喜欢她 - 我知道你会的
- Oh, I like her. - I knew you would.
Smith啊!
Smith!
Smith 你在哪儿 伙计?
Smith Where are you, mate?
我们不能让他们看见
We can't let them see us.
快! 到这儿来
Quick! Over here.
这个地方让我害怕
This place gives me the creeps.
野蛮人可能躲在任何地方
Savages could be hiding anywhere.
对 如果你发现一个 不要多想 尽管开枪就是
Aye. Well, if you spot one, don't ask questions. Just shoot.
小心你的脚 你个畸形儿!
Watch your feet, you big oaf!
不是我 是这棵树
It wasn't me. It was the tree.
哦 当然!
Oh, of course!
这棵树好像把它的根抬了一下...
The tree just felt like lifting its roots and...
我们赶快离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
- 啊哦! 快跑啊! - 啊哦!
- Ow! Run! - Ow!
但是Smith怎么办?
But what about Smith?
他已经是个大人了 他能够照顾自己的
He's a big lad. He can take care of himself.
我真高兴你们能站在我这边
I'm glad you're on our side.
这些古老的藤蔓 倒是还有些力气
There's still some snap in these old vines.
我最好在他们把所有人 都派来找我之前赶回去
I'd better get back before they send the whole camp out after me.
我们什么时候能再见面?
When will I see you again?
今天晚上 就在这儿
Meet me tonight. Right here.
嗯 我已经200年 没有碰到这种兴奋的事了
Well, I haven't had this much excitement in 200 years.
我到底在做什么? 我不应该再去见他了
What am I doing? I shouldn't be seeing him again.
我的意思是 我还想再见到他
I mean, I want to see him again.
谁不想? 我也想再见到他
Who wouldn't? I want to see him again.
但是仍然 一种内在的感觉...
But still, something inside...
在告诉我 这是对的
is telling me it's the right thing.
或许这就是你的梦
Perhaps it's your dream.
我的梦? 你是说他就是...
My dream? Do you think he's the one...
那个旋转的箭头所指向的?
the spinning arrow was pointing to?
战士们来了!
The warriors are here!
Pocahontas 你疯了吗? 你到底在做什么?
Pocahontas, are you crazy? What were you doing with one of them?
- 你在这儿! - Kocoum!
- There you are. - Kocoum!
看看他们! 现在我们有足够的勇士...
Look at them! Now we have enough warriors...
去摧毁那些白皮肤的魔鬼!
to destroy those white demons!
既然我们的兄弟们加入了...
Now that we are joined by our brothers...
我们就要去击败那些敌人
we will defeat this enemy.
父亲 我想和你谈谈
Father, I need to speak with you.
现在不行 我的女儿 首领们正在商量事情
Not now, my daughter. The council is gathering.
我们并不需要和他们打仗 一定有一条更好的路可走
We don't have to fight them! There must be a better way.
有时候我们的路是已经定了的
Sometimes our paths are chosen for us.
但是也许我们 可以试着和他们谈谈
But maybe we should try talking to them.
他们并不想谈判
They do not want to talk.
但是如果他们 其中一个真的想要呢...
But if one of them did want to talk...
你会听他的 是吗?
you would listen to him, wouldn't you?
- Pocahontas - 是吗?
- Pocahontas. - Wouldn't you?
我当然会 但是事情并不是那么简单
Of course I would. But it is not that simple.
没有什么事情会这么简单的
Nothing is simple any more.
别紧张 Thomas 是我
Easy, Thomas. It's me.
哦 John 我差点打中你
Oh, John. I could've killed you.
你这样瞄准是打不中我的
Not aiming like that, you couldn't.
当你射击的时候 两只眼睛都睁着
Keep both eyes open when you shoot.
你会瞄得准得多
You'll see twice as well.
Smith 你回来了!
Smith, there you are!
我们正四处找你
We were looking all over for you.
Smith! 你刚刚去哪儿了?
Smith! Where have you been?
我去观察地形了 长官
I was out scouting the terrain, sir.
聪明 那么你一定 知道印第安人的行踪了
Excellent. Then you must know the Indians' whereabouts.
这些信息对我们的 战役应该会有帮助的
We'll need that information for the battle.
什么战役?
What battle?
我们要把这些 野蛮人一次消灭干净
We will eliminate these savages once and for all.
不! 你不能那么做!
No! You can't do that!
哦 不能?
Oh, can't I?
听着 我们并不需要和他们打仗
Look, we don't have to fight them.
- John 你怎么了? - 我见过他们当中一个
- John, what's gotten into you? - I met one of them.
- 你什么?! - 一个野蛮人?
- You what?! - A savage?
他们不是野蛮人 他们能够帮助我们
They're not savages. They can help us.
他们了解这片土地
They know the land.
他们知道怎样在河里航行
They know how to navigate the rivers.
- 再看 这是食物 - 这是什么?
- And look. It's food. - What is it?
这个肯定比硬面饼和稀粥强
It's better than hardtack and gruel, that's for sure.
我喜欢稀粥
I like gruel.
他们不会给我们食物 你们这些笨蛋!
They don't want to feed us, you ninnies!
他们想要杀死我们! 我们所有的人!
They want to kill us! All of us!
他们拿走了我们的金子...
They've got our gold...
为了留住它 他们会做出任何事情!
and they'll do anything to keep it!
但是这儿没有金子
But there is no gold.
没有金子?
No gold?
我猜肯定是你的印第安小朋友告诉你的?
And I suppose your little Indian friend told you this?
没错
Yes.
谎言! 谎言! 一切都是谎言! 危险的小偷!
Lies! Lies! All of it! Murderous thieves!
在文明世界中他们没有立足之地
There's no room for their kind in civilized society.
但是这儿是他们的地盘!
But this is their land!
这是我的地盘! 我在这儿制定法律
This is my land! I make the laws here.
我说过任何人一旦发现了印第安人...
And I say anyone who so much as looks at an Indian...
而没有将他当场杀死的...
without killing him on sight...
将被判为叛国罪而处以绞刑!
will be tried for treason and hanged!
Pocahontas啊!
Pocahontas!
- Nakoma! - 不要出去
- Nakoma! - Don't go out there.
我为你撒过一次谎 不要让我再做一次
I lied for you once. Don't ask me to do it again.
我必须要这样做
I have to do this.
- 他是他们其中之一! - 你不了解他
- He's one of them! - You don't know him.
如果你去了那儿...
If you go out there...
你就背叛了你自己的族人
You'll be turning your back on your own people.
我在努力拯救我的族人
I'm trying to help my people.
Pocahontas 求你 你是我最好的朋友
Pocahontas, please. You're my best friend.
我不想看到你受到伤害
I don't want you to get hurt.
我不会的 我知道我自己在做什么
I won't. I know what I'm doing.
Pocahontas 不!
Pocahontas, no!
Ratcliffe不会让我们...
Ratcliffe wouldn't take us...
在这个世界什么都找不到
halfway around the world for nothin'.
但是如果Smith说得是真的呢?
But what if Smith is right?
如果真的没有金子该怎么办?
What if there is no gold?
如果你问我...
If you ask me...
Ratcliffe从我们离开伦敦的时候就在骗我们
Ratcliffe's been lying to us since we left London.
听着 你们这些白痴
Listen to you, ya bunch of idiots.
那些野蛮人不会吃了没事和我们打战的
Those savages didn't attack us for nothin'.
他们一定在隐藏着什么东西
They're hidin' somethin'.
如果他们真的有金子...
If they do have the gold...
我想我们会和他们打战的
I reckon we'll have to fight 'em.
要不太冷要不太热
Either too hot or too cool.
我从一到这儿就没舒服过
I haven't been comfortable since we got here.
哦 我也是 我痒得难受
Oh, I know. I've been itching a lot.
- 跟着他 - 是的 长官
- Follow him. - Yes, Governor.
我想知道他偷偷地跑去哪儿
I want to know where he's sneaking off to.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
如果你遇到什么印第安人
And if you happen to see any Indians,
开枪打死他
Shoot them.
哦 Thomas 你已经是一个差劲的水手
Oh, and Thomas, you've been a slipshod sailor
又是一个可怜的士兵
and a poor excuse for a soldier.
不要让我再次失望
Don't disappoint me again.
- Kocoum - 什么事?
- Kocoum. - What is it?
是关于Pocahontas的
It's Pocahontas.
怎么了? 她还好吗?
What's wrong? Is she all right?
我想她有麻烦了
I think she's in trouble.
大地在颤抖 孩子 发生什么事了?
The Earth is trembling, child. What's happened?
战士们在这儿!
The warriors are here!
- Pocahontas啊! - John啊!
- Pocahontas! - John!
听我说
Listen to me.
我们的人正在计划攻击你的族人
My men are planning to attack your people.
你得去通知他们
You've got to warn them.
也许现在阻止这些还不算太晚
Maybe it's not too late to stop this.
你得跟我一起回去 去和我父亲谈判
You have to come with me and talk to my father.
Pocahontas 谈判已经没有用了
Pocahontas, talking isn't going to do any good.
我已经努力地去和我们的人谈了...
I already tried talking to my men...
但是这片土地上的任何一件事情都让他们感到恐惧
but everything about this land has them spooked.
那是我见过的最奇怪的生物!
That's the strangest creature I've ever seen.
Percy啊?!
Percy?!
放松点 Percy! 到这儿来!
Easy, Percy! Come here!
Meeko 回来!
Meeko, come back!
你看这就是我的意思?
You see what I mean?
一旦双方准备开仗 谁也挡不住
Once two sides want to fight, nothing can stop them.
过来 你们俩都给我过来!
Come Come here, both of you!
好了! 好了! 他是一个朋友!
It's all right! It's all right! He's a friend!
坏! 坏狗! 坐下!
Bad! Bad dog! Sit!
- 你在干什么? Meeko! - Pency 回到这里来!
- What are you doing? Meeko! - Percy, get back here!
你在干什么? 停下来!
What are you doing? Stop that!
好了 够了!
All right, that's enough!
足够让你的体液沸腾
It's enough to make your sap boil.
现在 我有东西给你们看 看!
Now then, there's something I want to show you. Look.
波纹
The ripples.
他们什么意思?
What about them?
一开始很小
So small at first,
然后看他们扩散得多大
then look how they grow.
但是总得有人去开始
But someone has to start them.
他们不会听我们的
They're not going to listen to us.
年轻人 有时候正确的路
Young man, sometimes the right path
往往不是最简单的那条
is not the easiest one.
难道你不明白? 只有当战争停止了...
Don't you see? Only when the fighting stops...
你们才能在一起
can you be together.
好吧 我们去和你父亲谈谈
All right. Let's go talk to your father.
Kocoum! 不!
Kocoum! No!
Kocoum啊!
Kocoum!
放开他!
Leave him alone!
Kocoum! 停下来!
Kocoum! Stop!
双眼睁开
Both eyes open.
- Thomas! - 他...
- Thomas! - Is he...
你杀了他
You killed him.
- 我以为... - 离他远些!
- I thought that... - Get away from him!
Pocahontas 这样没有用的! 他只是...
Pocahontas, it won't help! He was only...
他杀了他!
He killed him!
Thomas 离开这儿!
Thomas, get out of here!
离开这儿!
Get out of here!
谁干的?
Who did this?
Pocahontas在野外树林里
Pocahontas was out in the woods.
Kocoum去找他 这个白人袭击了他
Kocoum went to find her and this white man attacked him.
你们的武器很厉害
Your weapons are strong,
但是现在我的怒火更厉害
but now our anger is stronger.
在太阳升起的时候 首先就将他处死!
At sunrise he will be the first to die!
但是 父亲...
But, Father...
我告诉过你待在部落里
I told you to stay in the village.
你违背了我
You disobeyed me.
你让你的父亲蒙羞!
You have shamed your father!
我只是想做点帮助
I was only trying to help.
就因为你的愚蠢 Kocoum死掉了!
Because of your foolishness, Kocoum is dead!
把他带走!
Take him away!
Kocoum只是想来保护我
Kocoum was just coming to protect me.
Pocahontas啊...
Pocahontas...
是我让Kocoum跟着你的
I sent Kocoum after you.
我很担心你
I was worried about you.
我原以为我做了件正确的事
I-I thought I was doing the right thing.
所有这些都是因我而起
All this happened because of me.
现在我再也见不到John Smith了
And now I'll never see John Smith again.
跟我来
Come with me.
Pocahontas想最后看一眼...
Pocahontas wants to look into the eyes...
那个杀了Kocoum的人
of the man who killed Kocoum.
最好快点
Be quick.
Pocahontas啊
Pocahontas.
我真是抱歉
I'm so sorry.
为了什么? 这件事吗?
For what? This?
比这还糟糕的困境 我都摆脱出来了
I've gotten out of worse scrapes than this.
现在想不起来了 但是...
Can't think of any right now, but...
如果我们不曾见过 事情也许不会这么糟糕
It would've been better if we'd never met.
这些事情都不会发生
None of this would've happened.
Pocahontas 看着我
Pocahontas, look at me.
我情愿明天就去死...
I'd rather die tomorrow...
也不要长寿 但不认识你
than live a hundred years without knowing you.
Pocahontas啊
Pocahontas.
- 我不能离开你 - 你不会离开我的
- I can't leave you. - You never will.
不管我发生什么事 我会跟你在一起的 永远
No matter what happens to me, I'll always be with you. Forever.
救命! 快救命啊! 救命! 救命!
Help! Somebody help! Help! Help!
- 别急 伙计 怎么了? - Smith! 他们抓住他了!
- Easy, lad. What is it? - It's Smith! They got him!
- 谁抓住他了? - 野蛮人!
- Who got him? - The savages!
- 野蛮人? - 他们抓住他了 把他带走了!
- Savages? - They captured him, dragged him off!
- 他们把他带去哪儿了? - 他们朝北去了
- Where'd they take him? - They headed north.
- 有多少人? - 我不知道 至少有十来个
- How many were there? - I don't know. At least a dozen.
- 可恶的畜生! - Ratcliffe是对的!
- Filthy beasts! - Ratcliffe was right!
太好了 Wiggins 我自己可不能计划的这么好
It's perfect, Wiggins. I couldn't have planned this better myself.
金子肯定是我的了
The gold is as good as mine.
我们得救他! 换了我们任何谁 他也会这么做的!
We've got to save him! He'd do the same for any of us!
- Thomas是对的! 我们得做点什么! - 我们应该做点什么
- Thomas is right! We've got to do somethin'! - And so we shall.
- 我跟你说过不能信这些野蛮人 - 对!
- I told you those savages couldn't be trusted. - That's right!
Smith想跟他们成为朋友 看看他们对他做了什么!
Smith tried to befriend them, and look what they've done to him!
- 嗯 对 - 而现在我宣布是时候去救我们勇敢的同志了
- Yeah, that's right. - But now I say it's time to rescue our courageous comrade.
天一亮 我们就进攻!
At daybreak, we attack!
对这些无赖我们还能期待什么呢
What can you expect from filthy little heathens
- 当有不同种族的时候就会发生这种事 - 没错
- Here's what you get when races are diverse - That's right.
# 他们的皮肤是地狱般的红色 他们只有死的时候才最乖 #
# Their skins are hellish red They're only good when dead #
# 他们是害虫 就像我所说的甚至更糟 #
# They're vermin, as I said and worse #
# - 他们是野蛮人 野蛮人 - 几乎不是人类 #
# - They're savages, savages - Barely even human #
# - 野蛮人 野蛮人 - 把他们赶出我们的海岸 #
# - Savages, savages - Drive them from our shore #
# 他们不像你和我 他们是恶魔 #
# They're not like you and me which means they must be evil #
# 我们要敲响战鼓 #
# We must sound the drums of war #
# 他们是野蛮人 野蛮人 肮脏尖叫着的魔鬼 #
# They're savages, savages Dirty shrieking devils #
# 现在我们敲响战鼓 #
# Now we sound the drums of war #
# 这是一场我们害怕的战争 那些白脸的都是魔鬼 #
# This is what we feared The pale face is a demon #
# 他们仅有的感觉是贪婪 #
# The only thing they feel at all is greed #
# 在那乳白色的皮肤之下 里面全都是空的 #
# Beneath that milky hide there's empatiness inside #
# 我怀疑他们会不会流血 #
# I wonder if they even bleed #
# - 他们是野蛮人 野蛮人 - 几乎不是人类 #
# - They're savages, savages - Barely even human #
# - 野蛮人 野蛮人 - 本质上是凶手 #
# - Savages, savages - Killers at the core #
# 他们和我们不一样 他们不能被信任 #
# They're different from us which means they can't be trusted #
# 我们要敲响战鼓 #
# We must sound the drums of war #
# - 他们是野蛮人 野蛮人 - 首先让我们来处理这个 #
# - They're savages, savages - First we deal with this one #
# - 然后我们敲响战鼓 - 野蛮人 野蛮人 #
# - Then we sound the drums of war - Savages, savages #
# 让我们去杀掉几个 伙计们! #
# Let's go get a few, men! #
# - 野蛮人 野蛮人 - 现在就靠你们了 各位 #
# - Savages, savages - Now it's up to you, men #
# - 野蛮人 - 野蛮人 #
# - Savages - Savages #
# 几乎不是人类 #
# Barely even human #
# 现在我们敲响 #
# Now we sound the drums #
# 战 #
# Of #
# 鼓 #
# War #
- 他们准备在太阳升起的时候处决他 Willow奶奶 - 你得去制止他们
- They're going to kill him at sunrise, Grandmother Willow. - You have to stop them.
- 我没有办法 - 孩子 记住你那个梦
- I can't. - Child, remember your dream.
我错了 Willow奶奶 我走错了一条路
I was wrong, Grandmother Willow. I followed the wrong path.
我感到很失落
I feel so lost.
指南针?
The compass?
旋转的指针
Spinning arrow.
这是你梦里的指针
It's the arrow from your dream.
我是对的! 它正指向他
I was right! It was pointing to him.
- 日出 - 还不晚 孩子
- Sunrise. - It's not too late, child.
让大地的灵魂来指引你
Let the spirits of the Earth guide you.
你知道你的路 孩子
You know your path, child.
现在跟随着它!
Now follow it!
# 就是这一天 #
# This will be the day #
我们走 各位!
Let's go, men!
# 就是今天早上了 #
# This will be the morning #
把那个囚犯带出来!
Bring out the prisoner!
# 我们要看着 他们死在烟尘中 #
# We will see them dying in the dust #
# 我不知道我能做什么 但我知道我必须去争取 #
# I don't know what I can do Still, I know I've got to try #
# - 现在就要让他们付出代价 - 鹰啊 帮我飞起来吧 #
# - Now we make 'em pay - Eagle, help my feet to fly #
# - 好 突袭 - 大山 让我的心灵变得伟大 #
# - Now, without a warning - Mountain, help my heart be great #
# 我们留给他们血骨和锈迹 #
# Now we leave 'em blood and bone and rust #
# - 大地和天空的灵魂 - 要么他们死 要么我们亡 #
# - Spirits of the Earth and sky - It's them or us #
# - 别拖太久 - 他们只是帮 #
# - Please don't let it be too late - They're just a bunch of #
# - 肮脏 烂臭的野蛮人 - 野蛮人 #
# - Filthy, stinking savages - Savages #
# - 魔鬼 - 恶魔 - 杀死他们! #
# - Demon - Devil - Kill them! #
# - 野蛮人 野蛮人 - 我们还等什么 #
# - Savages, savages - What are we waiting for #
# 摧毁他们邪恶的种族直到没有任何痕迹留下 #
# Destroy their evil race until there's not a trace left #
# - 战鼓 - 我们要敲起战鼓 #
# - How loud - We will sound the drums of war #
# - 多么嘹亮 - 我们要敲起战鼓 #
# - Are the drums of war - Now we sound the drums of war #
# - 现在我们看到了试图交好的下场 - 我们要敲起战鼓 #
# - Now we see what comes of trying to be chums - Now we sound the drums #
# - 是我所爱的一切的死去继续擂动 - 战 #
# - Is the death of all I love carried in the drumming of - Of #
# - 鼓 # - 不!
# - War # - No!
如果你要杀死他 你就先杀了我
If you kill him, you'll have to kill me too.
女儿 让开
Daughter, stand back.
我不! 我爱他 父亲
I won't! I love him, Father.
什么?
What?
看看你的四周 这就是你给我们带来的的仇恨之路
Look around you. This is where the path of hatred has brought us.
这是我选择的路 父亲 想想你的那条将会是怎样?
This is the path I choose, Father. What will yours be?
我女儿的话蕴涵了一种超乎她的年龄的智慧
My daughter speaks with a wisdom beyond her years.
我们都是带着 一颗愤怒的心来的...
We have all come here with anger in our hearts...
但是她是带着勇气和理解来的
but she comes with courage and understanding.
从今天开始如果再会有杀戮的话...
From this day forward, if there is to be more killing...
那绝对不会是我发起的
it will not start with me.
释放他
Release him.
这正是一个好机会! 开火!
Now's our chance! Fire!
- 不! - 什么?
- No! - What?
- 他们释放了他 - 他们并不想打仗
- They let him go. - They don't want to fight.
这是个骗局! 你们还不明白吗? 开火!
It's a trick! Don't you see? Fire!
好吧 我自己来解决
Fine. I'll settle this myself.
不!
No!
John啊!
John!
- 你打中了他! - 是他自己... 扑上去的 这是他自己的错
- You shot him! - He stepped right... right into it. It's his own fault.
- Smith一直都是对的 - 我们真不应该听了你的话
- Smith was right all along. - We never should've listened to you.
- 把他的枪抢过来! - 叛徒!
- Get the gun! - Traitors!
放开我 我说! 你们怎么敢这样!
Unhand me, I say! How dare you!
- 用镣铐把他锁起来! - 你们都会因为这件事被绞死的!
- Put him in chains! - I'll see you all hanged for this!
把他的嘴也堵起来!
And gag him as well!
- 他能够挺过去吗 Thomas? - 最好尽快把他送回伦敦 就好了
- Is he gonna make it, Thomas? - The sooner he gets back to England, the better.
- 那 希望他一帆风顺 - 船准备好了吗?
- Well, let's hope the wind is with him. - Is the ship ready yet?
随时可以出发 在装载最后一批货物了
Any minute now. Just loadin' the last bit of cargo.
你们怎么敢这样! 立刻放开我!
How dare you! Untie me at once!
我会要了你们的脑袋!
I'll have your heads for this!
他总是把自己想得太高了
And he came so highly recommended.
船已经准备好了 我们最好把你抬到甲板上 我们会错过潮汐的
The ship's almost ready. We'd better get you on board. We'll lose the tide.
不 先不要
No, not yet.
- 她说了她会来的 - 看
- She said she'd be here. - Look.
回去是他生存下去的唯一希望 如果待在这儿 他会死的
Going back is his only chance. He'll die if he stays here.
给 这是Willow奶奶的树皮
Here. It's from Grandmother Willow's bark.
它可以止痛
It'll help with the pain.
什么痛? 比这个更严重的伤我都有过
What pain? I've had worse pain than this.
一时间想不到是什么伤了 但是...
Can't think of any right now, but...
你在我们的族人中 永远都是受欢迎的
You are always welcome among our people.
谢谢 亲爱的兄弟
Thank you, my brother.
我原以为你不喜欢陌生人
I thought you didn't like strangers.
我母亲的项链
My mother's necklace.
再见 Percy
See ya, Percy.
和我一起走吧?
Come with me?
你必须选择你自己的路
You must choose your own path.
我离不开这儿
I'm needed here.
那么我留下来陪你
Then I'll stay with you.
不 你必须回去
No. You have to go back.
- 但是我离不开你 - 你永远不会离开我
- But I can't leave you. - You never will.
不论发生什么事 我会一直和你在一起
No matter what happens, I'll always be with you.
直到永久
Forever.
- 祝你好运 伙计 - 一路平安 John
- Good luck, lad. - Godspeed, John.
- 船员准备好了吗? - 是的 先生!
- The crew a-ready? - Aye, sir!
扬起帆!
Set the mainsails!
起锚!
Weigh anchor!
- 上桅帆! - 是 先生!
- Let go of the topgallants! - Aye, sir!
谢谢观赏
-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
hd.cnscg.com
# 如果我不曾认识你 #
# If I never knew you #
# 如果我没有感到这份爱 #
# If I never felt this love #
# 我将不会知道 #
# I would have no inkling of #
# 生命原来可以这么珍贵 #
# How precious life can be #
# 我对你如此地感激 #
# And I'm so grateful to you #
# 我将会在失落中 #
# I'd have lived my whole life through #
# 度过一生 #
# Lost forever #
# 如果我不曾认识你 #
# If I never knew you #
# 我会很安全 但是真的不完整 #
# I'd be safe but half as real #
# 从来不会感觉到 #
# Never knowing I could feel #
# 那么强烈那么真挚的爱 #
# A love so strong and true #
# - 哦 如果我不曾认识你 - 我就不会后悔 #
# - Oh, if I never knew you - There's no moment I'd regret #
# - 如果我不曾感到这份爱 - 自从我们见面的那一刻 #
# - If I never knew your love - Since the moment that we met #
# - 我就不可能知道 - 如果我们的时间去得太快 #
# - I would have no inkling of - If our time has gone too fast #
# - 生命是多么宝贵 - 我已经到了生命的最后一刻 #
# - How precious life can be - I've lived at last #
# 对 对 #
# Yeah, yeah #
# 我想我们的爱会如此美丽 #
# I thought our love would be so beautiful #
# 如此美丽 #
# So beautiful #
# 不知如何我们让整个世界充满光明 #
# Somehow we'd make the whole world bright #
# 我想我们的爱会如此美丽 #
# I thought our love would be so beautiful #
# 我们将黑暗变成光明 #
# We'd turn the darkness into light #
# 我的心仍然一直在说这是对的 #
# And still my heart is saying we were right #
# 我们是对的 #
# We were right #
# - 而如果我不曾认识你 - 如果我不曾认识你 #
# - And if I never knew you - If I never knew you #
# 我在这个世界上活得 #
# I'd have lived my whole life through #
# 如此空荡荡就像天空 #
# Empty as the sky #
# 从来不知道为什么 #
# Never knowing why #
# 永久失去 #
# Lost forever #
# 如果我不曾认识 #
# If I never knew #
# 你 #
# You #
# 对 #
# Yeah #
# 你认为你所登陆的 土地都是你的 #
# You think you own whatever land you land on #
# 大地只是一个没有生命的东西 #
# The earth is just a dead thing you can claim #
# 但是我知道每一块石头 每一棵树木 每一个生灵 #
# But I know every rock and tree and creature #
# 都有它的生命 有它的灵魂 #
# Has a life, has a spirit #
# 有它的名字 #
# Has a name #
# 你认为只有长得像你那样 #
# You think the only people who are people #
# 看问题想问题都跟你一样的才是真正的人 #
# Are the people who look and think like you #
# 但是如果你沿着一个陌生人的足迹走下去 #
# But if you walk the footsteps of a stranger #
# 你会学到你从来不知道的事情 你从来不知道的事情 #
# You'll learn things you never knew you never knew #
# 你曾经听到过野狼嚎叫 #
# Have you ever heard the wolf cry #
# 对着蓝色天空里的明月 #
# To the blue corn moon #
# 或让苍鹰告诉你他去过哪儿 #
# Or let the eagle tell you where he's been #
# 你能和着大山的声音唱歌吗? #
# Can you sing with all the voices of the mountain #
# 你能用风的颜色来绘画吗? #
# Can you paint with all the colours of the wind #
# 枫树能长得多么的高? #
# How high does the sycamore grow #
# 如果你把它砍了 #
# If you cut it down #
# 你将永远不会知道 #
# Then you'll never know #
# 你将永远不会听到野狼嚎叫 #
# And you'll never hear the wolf cry #
# 对着蓝色天空里的明月 #
# To the blue corn moon #
# 不管我们的皮肤是白色还是棕色 #
# For whether we are white or copapaer-skinned #
# 我们需要和着大山的声音来歌唱 #
# We need to sing with all the voices of the mountain #
# 我们需要用风的颜色来绘画 #
# We need to paint with all the colours of the wind #
# 你会拥有大地而且 #
# You can own the Earth and still #
# 所有你将拥有的是大地直到 #
# All you'll own is earth until #
# 你能够用风的颜色 #
# You can paint with all the colours #
# 来 #
# Of #
# 绘画 #
# The wind #